hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways for course creators and
coaches to grow increase their income
and make way more money than they are
right now with proven
methods that work to sell your courses
and coaching online we host Live Events
uh every month this podcast is full of
lessons for you that will transform your
life and to today I want to talk about
something that uh I've never done a
podcast episode on
before uh it's new for me I'm a little
nervous to do it but I'm going to go for
it and it's really a a tell all about my
uh childhood teenage years
and uh getting into business and what
got me to where I am today so really if
you talk if you're if you're talking
about it it's an autobiograph
autobiographical
episode um but there's going to be
lessons throughout this and so it's not
just gonna be me reminiscing about the
past we're going to tie this to lessons
that you can learn okay and so
uh earliest memory I have is of my mom
dating uh a couple of
guys um I was born my mom was a single
mom raised
me um she
was on
welfare um we would get a lot of our
food from the local church Food Bank
growing up we didn't have much at all
which is at such a juxa position from
where my mom is today one of the one of
the
wealthiest people that I know uh
financially as well
as relationally spiritually mentally and
an inspiration to me is what she has
done in her resilience and if there's
one lesson that you're going to get out
of this here today it's a lesson of
resilience not letting where you came
from destroy you not letting where you
started from stop you from what you
dream of and this all started with a
dream you know I have been a dreamer for
my whole life and I've always had Big
Dreams uh but I I
was disconnected from being able to
really accomplish them until
recently um because I struggled with my
own mental health my own mental health
journey and if I share anything with you
here today is that if you grew up like I
did and you have childhood trauma you
have Trauma from work trauma you have
Trauma
from just you've been hurt by people and
you're noticing
triggers like if you get angry and lash
out at people okay that's that's what
was happening with
me is somebody could push my buttons
enough and uh Loose Cannon would blow up
at at at anybody and then kind of back
off tuck my tail between my legs not
intending to hurt anybody but just
that's all I knew and it was to like let
them know like hey you don't scare me is
kind of what it was and that was my
biggest thing that was that was you
don't scare me is kind of the motto that
I lived by for so
long um so the earliest memory that I
had growing up was of my mom dating some
guys and and I felt the pressure to be a
good boy so
that we could find a dad find a guy to
take care of us and things like that and
so uh some of youall know my mom
divorced the man that she married after
20 plus 25 plus
years
um you
know I don't have much to say about that
that's that that's a tough one for me
it's funny I feel like I'm like yeah
there's there a lot I still have to
process there that I haven't fully
processed and I think that there's some
going to be some beauty that comes of
that but what I have processed through
is we're going to be talking about here
today you know I've struggled with
alcohol I've struggled with uh going to
jail three times I've struggled with um
and and and some people may see this as
a character flaw and and an all trust
that they have in me is now destroyed I
I understand that if that's the standard
that you have for your life I I applaud
you for that um for those of you that
you know aren't looking for a perfect
person who's never made a mistake
um can I get an amen like people that
are actually like all of us are because
I think that we've all made mistakes but
some people are looking for perfect
people that they can listen to I'm not
that and so if that's what you're
looking for I'm sorry I'm going to
disappoint you uh
but the for everybody else who's willing
to you
know talk about the stuff that maybe we
only talk about behind closed doors talk
about the private stuff talk about the
stuff that makes us feel
uncomfortable you're going to like this
and you're going to like this story and
you're going to like um what has
happened from it you know in the last
year my wife and I have built and grown
our own business to multi-million doll
status our son is almost 12 months old
uh we bought a beautiful house with a
pool uh um in the Austin Texas
area and
um really I could say everything that I
imagined and that I dreamed that I
wanted my life to be that's what I'm
living today and so that's why I've not
talked about any of this prior to today
because I didn't feel
like I had a leg to stand on as somebody
who was happy with the life that he
lived I'm happy with the life that I'm
living today very grateful work towards
the next level what is the next level 2x
3x in our income reaching an 8 figure
level where we're making over a million
dollar a month that's the or or over at
least
$833,000 a month basically is is eight
figures and so that's what that's what
my next level goal is right now right
now we you know I'm grateful for where
we're at it's an incredible life my
goodness but you you know I've seen we
we've built multiple eight figure
companies my mom and I did in the
coaching and course space I worked with
a friend of mine Rick Peno we built a
eight figure coaching and course
business with Rick Pino um and so I've
been around course creators and coaches
that are making over $10 million in
profit a
year and that's been like the the the
tribe that I've hung out with for the
longest the longest time okay and so but
just a little bit of like my background
in story is you know I have I have
memories of being with my grandmother
when my mom was in a psychiatric ward
which created abandonment issues I have
memories of my mom blowing up at me
verbally as a child uh I have you know
which terrified me completely I have
memories of being brutally beaten by my
dad to the point that it
made me bleed
so you know that was
hard we got we all have hard upbringings
some of y'all might hear what I'm saying
and say wow that was easy that sounds
like Cakewalk compared to what I had so
listen we're not here to compare our
wounds we're not here to compare that
you know I
um I grew up in a church that was
emotionally and mentally
abusive
uh cultic thinking and teaching it's
very cult-like
I was taught this thing called worm
theology that we have to see ourselves
as lower than
worms as Christians in order for God to
like us and that God actually hated me
is what I was taught and that it was my
job to save everybody for the kingdom
for this God that hates them uh or else
you know I am just I am not a good
Christian that's what I was taught
growing up this idea that manipulation
of human beings choices and being able
to control what other people choose to
do is the equivalent
to a Godly
lifestyle sad right and I'm sure some of
y'all like like that gives Christianity
a bad name and we used to say that gosh
there's so many Christians that give
Christianity a bad name and it was
because they were living a Godless
lifestyle they were living with any
mistakes whatsoever you know so
perfectionism was just the way of
living growing up and
and if I didn't want to go to hell or
displease God which I didn't believe
that I could lose my salvation but
um you know we were we were taught that
like like you can't
lose uh the sa the salvation of Jesus
Christ on the cross who died for your
sins through the
blood
um but you better not do anything
wrong so that's that's what it was and
so that's why
I am such a proponent of this Freedom
message having Freedom not operating in
perfectionism being willing to just do
what you want without worry about what
other people think about you that's why
I purport that so often I have people
who hate that I purport that they think
it's evil violent terrible bad for
people
whatever
but not being able to like choose the
life that I want to
live and having to basically Al live to
serve God growing
up uh it made
me at when I turned
18 leave the home you know I I struggled
with pornography as a teenager I
struggle with pornography as a young
man
and I went off and tried to
recreate uh the lifestyle that I had
seen from rap music videos and
pornography basically uh that was the
blueprint of life that I had in front of
me I mean
so understand that that's not a pretty
picture right
there and so in
that I I had to
grow I was also homeschooled at the same
time as all this I was not in a normal
school um and all my friends were just
from church and honestly I had great
friends at church and I remember my
friend JC we uh we used to get together
and um play Nintendo my happiest
memories were playing Nintendo I used to
go over to Bill van dijk's house and we
would in fact he had this poster on his
wall if you see I have a poster in my
office it's a Corvette poster uh Bill
had this on his wall that poster you
know uh The Legend of Zelda series I
used to play
this whoops this series at Bill's house
this video games so my love for video
games My Love for video games came in
during that that time period because it
was like it was something that I
enjoyed when everything felt chaotic and
it felt like I had freedom so my freedom
came from playing video games which is
why you know I I enjoy playing video
games to this day they help me relax
they help me calm down my nervous system
and things like that
and and but I also love business
business and I love helping people
succeed I love helping people break up
with patterns that they have in their
life that are stopping them I love
helping
people be able to take action and
actually start closing sales in a
business you know I used to be really
afraid of what everybody thought about
me um and it's because I was taught you
know you better not do anything wrong
and anybody see it or think wrong of you
cuz if somebody thinks wrong of you well
then it must be true and that the truth
and reality is actually in what other
people's opinions are and that is what I
was raised
with was this Firm
Foundation that I must please everybody
and make everybody happy for Safety and
Security and that was the message that I
went into the business world with I
started working with a company named
Danny johnson.com help put together
video products and truthfully it was a
very that was a very religious
experience um they were a bit cult like
cultic as well yeah I'll say it some of
y'all still follow them they were not
they were not very healthy um and you
know uh I mean the fact that like me
even saying that makes me think well
they're going to send me a cease and
desist legal letter to take this podcast
episode down because they were so
concerned about controlling what other
people do
um or or saying that what I'm saying is
liable and slander I that's not that's
literally what how they were and
so understand that I went from like one
thing that I grew up with to something
pretty similar to it uh but it was my
first time around millionaires it was my
first time around people that were
making a lot of money and it it changed
my life being able to see that which was
awesome and hey I wish them the best I
hope that they grow out of this insecure
way of living that IED us to be a part
of okay this this need to control
everybody that's why I talk so often
about letting go of control I think it's
a powerful technique that can help us in
business letting go of control over
other people learning to accept other
people letting go of control
of once you make a
choice just seeing what happens taking
on experiment ation mindset you know
that's not what I grew up like that's
not how I grew
up but then learning to walk through
that has taught me how to be successful
every single person that I know in
business Danny Johnson included did so
by taking a risk and they had team
members that were willing to take risks
same with my mom and yet we often
believe that we got to be perfect that
we got to do everything perfect before
we launch what we're doing and put it
out there it's ridiculous
you don't have to be perfect that's a
big facade because all the people that
you think are perfect that aren't
actually perfect they just fake it
really well
okay so anyways uh from there I um got a
taste of alcohol drank a lot got
arrested a couple times for alcohol
related
stuff um and then started working with
my mom we
helped uh her build I helped her build
that business we helped thousands of
coaches and course creators and online
marketer people who wanted to learn
online marketing for years that you know
she started that business I think around
2007 2009
is uh coaching and mentoring people
prior to that my mom had actually ran an
online kitchen wear store that was
actually making millions of dollars and
so we grew up without any money think of
so y'all are
like where does that fit um we grew up
without a lot of money and then the
money came in when my mom launched a a
website a kitchen wear
store uh that was online and and you can
even see the website if you go to
archive.org you can type in health for
you ministry.org which is funny she she
had the name health for you
Ministry uh on the title of the
actual uh business for some reason she
felt like that would like legitimize it
a little bit
more
um you know Health yeah it's let me see
is it www yeah oh no they don't have it
on here is
it.com it's do there it is yeah so this
goes back to 99 but it started way way
before 99 I
think I'm pulling I'm actually for those
of you that are not on the video we have
a YouTube version of this podcast and so
I'm actually pulling up my mom's first
uh
original uh website where I can actually
show
you
um you know what it looks like and and
it's having trouble pulling it just a
little bit right now that's
okay um but it was uh it says was not
archived interesting
but it says it was archived so yeah so
they're having some trouble with
that
um after that my mom went into network
marketing and that's how I got connected
with Danny johnson.com
because Danny Johnson was a trainer and
coach in the network marketing industry
so again remember I teach coaches
trainers and mentors Danny Johnson was a
trainer and Mentor in the network
marketing space my mom was a client of
Danny
Johnson oh here it is here's one of the
first here's the first website 99 look
at
that
um you can go a little bit further and
you can actually like see my mom's face
will actually pull up on there too which
is pretty cool but
um so my mom was a client of this coach
and Mentor Danny Johnson to get better
uh in her business and so you can see
this is like if you go to my mom's site
of real change.com back in
2004 it was a
optin for a network marketing business
it was a lead
magnet
and let's see
2006 and I actually built these lead
magnets right here yep I built this one
right here powered by Design desire to
design and if you click on that it'll
take you owned and operated by Jeremiah
Kowski created by desire to design yep
cuz that's what I did I did website
design I did uh video production I did
content Management Systems graphic
design and I I put these little sites
together so you can see here training
for success with Danny
Johnson uh and then my mom talking about
like her Mission serving this is my mom
right here helping people make uh the
six figure income with this network
marketing company okay and so that's how
I got kind of into that world with
coaches and course creators and all that
and and that's what we help people do
today is that
we we help them find clients on the
internet build the best lead magnets
build the best landing pages build the
best offers that get clients and that's
what we're hosting an event to do um
right now but you know I
remember I remember growing
up
and
wishing that uh you know we were taught
this thing called The Rapture about
Jesus coming back
and wishing that the Rapture wouldn't
happen you know until I uh had the
chance to have a SE have sex with a a
woman it's funny that was like my my
Teenage Dream you know was that and
obviously you know you have I have a son
so that's
happened DB stupid but what I'm talking
about is that you know I lived in so
much fear and so much worry and so much
shame in so much
guilt
and you know
I was only happy when I felt like I was
doing everything perfect when everything
that I did was
perfect
and when I moved out of my parents house
I just kind of went crazy started
partying started
drinking um a
lot DJing I djed a lot
turntables uh here in Austin Texas where
I live right now
back um back in like 2009
DJing out
here and so like I mean that was a while
ago too that was like 14 years
ago so I've been on this journey for a
while that was 14 years ago and I would
build these landing pages and these
websites and I would start to put
together the offers for my mom's
business and I helped even through the
alcohol even like it sounds like okay
like you destroyed your life
no throughout all that I was very
productive I helped put together a lot
of the DVD products for Danny Johnson I
helped my mom build her business uh to
multiple eight
figures um I actually stopped drinking
alcohol
completely about 2 and 1 half years ago
and so um haven't had any since then
sometimes I'll have maybe a
a kombucha or
a non-alcoholic
beer uh but they have such a minuscule
amount um that it doesn't affect
me in that same way
so um but I don't do that that often I'm
actually on a health protocol right now
I'm taking I'm on a detox protocol right
now to heal my gut to heal
my inflammation and it's funny is I feel
a lot less fear right now healing my gut
and inflammation and and truthfully one
of the number one things that changed my
life and it allowed me to be able to
build my business to be over seven
figures was working with a therapist on
my mental health healing from the trauma
of my past of my childhood of the things
that didn't go how I wished they would
and and those are just a few of the
highlights you know I anchor some of
those down
um some people again like I said would
say my childhood was nothing it was not
painful it wasn't like if we're
comparing trauma but again that's not
healthy it felt so big to me that it
crippled me and it stopped me from being
able to be successful even when I had
skills and I doubted myself and I and I
presented myself to the world as
somebody who was not trustworthy because
I was so concerned with making everybody
happy you know when we worry about
making everybody in our life happy and
never doing anything wrong and never
pissing anybody
off when we worry about
that we're divorcing our actual real
identity because how we really are we're
hiding behind a
facade and this is why getting some
healing helps because honestly the
reason why we hide that is we're ashamed
and we're ashamed of what's coming
through the surface you know I was
ashamed of a lot of stuff sexual
desires
um you know beliefs that I had beliefs
that I held on to people that I hung out
with even I was ashamed to even tell
people this
story you know and truthfully I tell
story some people say I made it up it's
not real none of it actually happened
I'm like I don't know how you could say
that it's really
weird it's literally
exactly what
happened um but you know you're never
going to please everybody and you're
never going to convince
everybody that they should love you or
buy into what you're talking about and
so
part of what I teach people is you got
to lay down that desire to make
everybody
happy there will be people that are
disappointed there will be haters there
will be people that disagree with you
that say you're wrong for doing the
thing that's the very best thing that
you do you know I have people all the
time that come to me and say Jeremiah
you are a I'm not even going to repeat
what they say it's hurtful it's untrue
it's not worth
repeating but they're so convinced of
that and it's funny is they would rather
I
lie and say oh you caught
[Music]
me I'm really all those things which
aren't true but they would rather I do
that than actually be truthful to you
and tell you what I've accomplished what
I've done the multiple eight figure
coaching companies that we built the
millions of dollars that we've sold the
lives that we've impacted over the years
and I used to shrink back and hold back
from sharing my story with people
because I didn't want it to seem too big
for people I don't want it to seem too
unbelievable to people and I was so
concerned with making everybody like me
and approve of me and think good things
about
me and now I give up that worrying give
up managing my reputation all the time I
had people tell me gosh if you don't
manage your reputation it means you're
trash and I'm like no it doesn't it
actually means that I my reputation is
legitimate and I'm authentic and I don't
need to worry about what people think
about me because I love whatever they
think about
me and I and I want you to either love
me or hate me I'm not trying to get
people to hate me but they naturally do
they naturally will and even there might
be some of you who are listening to this
right now you're just like cringing at
everything that I'm saying I understand
that it's totally
fine doesn't bother
me you know one of the great things
that's really helped me in my life is
stoicism uh the meditations of Marcus
aelius
specifically and learning and also some
of the writings of Ryan Halliday and his
daily stoic content this idea that we
don't let what happened to us hurt us or
Define us and that even on a day-to-day
basis we're stronger than the situations
that we're actually experiencing or
feeling and that's a that's a really
bastardized version of what stoicism
actually is but that's what I've taken
from it is it it's it's a tool for
strength you
know I'm I'm still a Christian I went to
church this
morning love going to church I I love
God I love Jesus uh still believe in
Jesus Christ you know go to a
non-denominational Christian Church
that's a little bit more on the H it's
on the holy spirit filled Pentecostal
bent uh we grew up
being taught that the Holy Spirit isn't
real that it's a that it's actually a
demon and any manifestations of the Holy
Spirit are actually demonic is is what I
was taught growing up
so I actually swung that pendulum all
the way over to the other side and now
I've kind of find a found a little bit
of some some balance in there I think
you can go way extreme to one side or
the other and neither of those are
healthy extremes are not
healthy very much at all so under
understand that you know you could rely
so much on therapy you could rely so
much
on um one denomination of Christianity
or another that it's not even healthy
anymore at that point but it helped you
through maybe a season you know it's
kind of like being addicted to video
games if all I did was play video games
that's unhealthy but the way that I use
it I
supplement video games sometimes when I
just I have moments where I feel like I
just I need to play a video game and it
it it creates creative Pathways in my
brain in those moments when I really
need to play a video game it unlocks
certain levels of creativity that I need
it unlocks certain things that I need to
be able
to experience all the things in life
that I want to experience and
so what I want to encourage you is this
is get to know your triggers
get to know the things that feel
uncomfortable understand why you do what
you do learn human psychology your
ability to close sales and business is
tied to your ability to understand human
beings and what motivates them overall
and I teach you this in my courses I
teach you this in my
classes don't let what tried to break
you and hurt you
when
today we all have experienced what we
experienced we've all gone through
certain things we've all had things
happen you
know I've missed out on at least a
million dollars in profits that I could
have made years
ago
because I didn't work on my mental
health and so the way I was thinking
actually led me down a path to miss out
on massive Financial breakthrough
opportunities that were very good very
healthy very very sustainable yet I ran
away from them because I was
afraid to piss people off I was afraid
to do the wrong thing
okay so I had to grow in this area and
I've
had people that hate me it's fine don't
doesn't bother
me but there's a group of people that
love me and they love what I talk about
and they love connecting with me and
they love this story and they're they're
glad and they're thankful for what I'm
talking about you know I don't ever want
to say any of this to dishonor my
parents or dishonor my family
or
gosh but certain activities aren't
honorable
either and the sooner we can start
talking about the things that maybe we
hold behind closed
doors the sooner we are willing
to shine a flashlight on what's not
working and say okay what can I learn
from this how can I solve this how can I
resolve this what levers can I pull to
fix what's not
working and we start in our homes we
start in our families we start in our
relationships and then that oozes into
the business we start with our
health you know I can tell you
this
there were things in my life in my
business that I was avoiding looking at
and as soon as I've started to look at
them and not be afraid to look at
certain things in my business that will
benefit me it's unlocked brand new
possibilities the thing that you're
running away from right now is your
future
breakthrough it is it's right directly
connected to the thing that you're
running away from that you're fearful of
the most most the most
fearful and when you actually understand
that
fully you can change your life you can
become a
multi-millionaire most people cannot
make a million dollars
because they're too stuck in trying to
make everybody happy around them instead
of making themselves happy and actually
doing the things that they want to do
when is the last time you did something
because you wanted to do it not because
you had to do it not because you were
obligated to do it when was the last
time that you sacrificed yourself you
put yourself into a situation where you
had to do something where you felt
obligated to do it that is taught in our
upbringing that we have to do it even if
we don't want to I didn't want
to be forbidden from listening to rock
music
and only allowed to listen to classical
music which I think was great it helped
my brain I play classical piano I love
it I think it's amazing but like come on
that was unreasonable I think and now I
become like a sort of a like I said
remember I said I djed I became sort of
like a
music uh
eclectic music knower of All Things
Music
related over
all and it's probably because I wasn't
allowed to listen to a lot of different
music so now I know all the music you
know is is is that you know so gosh if
you look at your life and your past and
and and take what I've talked about just
now as a blueprint it will unlock For
You
patterns of behavior and
influences that you can
rewire to then POS positively affect
your future which will then unlock your
income by building a new skill set I
will teach you if you want to create a
course if you want to create a coaching
program and then you want to sell it you
want to make six figures and you want to
make a million dollars I can teach you
how to do that start to
finish we have clients that have done
that and surpassed it like Rick Peno I
remember my mom and I were working with
Jennifer Alwood seeing her surpass
the revenue that we had even seen for
her you know working with my uh previous
client Joshua Giles over
$140,000 a month being able to build
$160,000 a month business for
myself it's incredible and
so don't let what tried to break you
what tried to stop you dictate your life
you're going to have to take action
you're going to have to do the hard
things you're going to have to do what
feels uncomfortable you're going to have
to learn how to sell you know there's a
book that I share with people these are
two books that I share in my uh coaching
group The The Ultimate Sales letter how
to write words that sell and now we use
AI to help with a lot of that but this
one is so valuable the way of the Wolf
by Jordan
bort you know I don't I don't uh endorse
his lifestyle but I love his book it's
incredible cuz it's one of the best
sales books on the planet about building
trust with people to get them to buy
what it is that you have to offer and
most people are just really not good at
sales it's not any fault of their own or
any reason that they are subpar some
people take it personally when I say
they need to get better at sales they
need to get better at communication I
think we can all improve in our ability
to communicate and use words to connect
with people
okay and when it comes to the words that
get people to say yeah okay that makes
sense and then they give you like
thousands of dollars afterwards that's
salesmanship ability and that's a skill
set that you need to learn that you need
to grow in CU then all you got to do is
you just got to gather people in front
of
you get like 50 to 100 people on a zoom
call on a video could even be a podcast
episode and then use that communication
ability to tap into their thinking and
their mind to
trigger positively
the belief that you can help them
accomplish the thing that you can help
people accomplish with your course or
coaching program and that the best
chance for them to achieve that goal is
by purchasing what you have to
offer I say this all the time I think
the best chance that anybody who's
listening to this has first off
subscribe to this podcast listen
subscribe to YouTube but joining my
client growth accelerator
program because we take it seriously the
results of our clients and we have more
positive six and seven figure case
studies than most any coaching program
that I've ever seen in fact we have some
of the most seven fig results from this
system from the system that we
teach the system that I taught when I
worked with my mom when I was the CEO of
my mom's company we were growing that
business and we built that business to a
multi-million doll Enterprise
there's a
process that works and that's what I
teach you and that's what I teach our
clients and that's what I teach on my
free events that's what the other
podcast episodes on this podcast are
about this one's a little bit longer of
an episode I wanted to go a little bit
longer on this but hear me
out you don't have to stay stuck making
the kind of money you're making right
now dream
bigger connect with me and learn to sell
you can find people on social media we
teach how to use Facebook ads and then
you can create an offer and sell a
course for
$11,000 to to 50 people that's 50 Grand
right there okay understand that 100
people spending $2,000 that's
$200,000 and those are normal those are
actually very conservative numbers to
the type of
to the system that we teach you and that
we show you how to do okay so I'd love
to connect with you join me for one of
my live events that we're
hosting share with me how this podcast
episode has inspired you has taught you
maybe things that you didn't know I
truly believe that any area where you're
stuck right now you can break through
from and I'd love to help you do that as
well so grow your life everybody and we
will talk soon have a good
[Applause]
one
sh